Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/yesiamrocks (LinkedIn) yesiam.rocks/ (Personal)

Top Skills

User Experience (UX)
User Interface Design
Web Animation

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Bangla (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

PRINCE2® Project Management Certifications

QA Studio Certified

Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional

HTML5 Studio Certified

Honors-Awards

mBillionth award South Asia 2012 CSS Author

Shafayetul Islam Pavel, PRINCE2® MCPS

UX/UI Designer | Specializing in UX/UI and Web animation | Creator of cssanimation.io and Scrollyjs.com

Dhaka

Summary

Hi, my name is Pavel. I'm a UI/UX Designer and web animator, who has been building websites as a hobby since 2009 and as a professional since 2011. Received mBillionth award South Asia 2012. Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP) with over 11 years of experience. Designed 3+ responsive website and mobile UI per month with 99% client satisfaction. During the day, I'm working with Oath/Yahoo in the ServicEngine Ltd. In the past, I have also worked for Microsoft by GraphicPeople as a Web developer.

Having worked on hundreds of web projects, including most recently on the successful One Creative by Oath/Yahoo. I lead a production team of over 24 front-end developers and worked with some of the biggest brands in this planet including Microsoft, Oath, Nokia, Dell, Cricket Australia, and HSBC.

I maintain a blog at www.cssanimation.io/readmore where I write tips, tricks and bookmarks on web development, design and web animation. I love sharing knowledge and have given over 10 invited talks at UI/UX and Web Animation conferences.

I strongly believe in open source and have started several popular open source projects, such as CSSanimation.io and Scrollyjs.com and many others.

What I can do

- Design what you want I like to keep it simple. My goals are to focus on typography, content and conveying the message that you want to send.
- Develop what you need I'm a developer, so I know how to create your website to run across devices using the latest technologies available.

Dribbble Profile: www.dribbble.com/yesiamrocks Behance Profile: www.behance.net/yesiamrocks Github Profile: www.github.com/yesiamrocks

If you want to collaborate on crafting an amazing experience for people or just fancy saying hey – you are very welcome to contact me, find me at info.bdpavel@gmail.com.

Experience

SEBPO

6 years 3 months

Creative Team Lead
October 2019 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Senior UI/UX Designer November 2015 - Present (6 years 3 months) Dhaka, Bangladesh

Representing a fortune 500 company. Working in a fast paced environment and producing a high volume of websites and landing pages. Design and implement graphics for Oath. Creating static & HTML5 Banner ads for 1 Creative Platform. Carrying out ad-hoc tasks as requested by the Project Manager.

- Lead UI/UX website designer for Yahoo/Oath team. Designed an average of
 3+ major website per month with 99% client satisfaction scores.
- Handled all composition, color, illustration, typography, and branding for client projects. Turned in projects an average of 5% faster than targets.
- Developed the retina compatible 100+ responsive website with bootstrap raised UX scores by 35% and, of course, a bunch of JavaScript features, also ensuring coding structure follows W3C web standards.
- Create the HTML5 Banner ads using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google
 Web Designer and Adobe Animate for DoubleClick, Yahoo/Oath, Sizmek, and
 AccuWeather.
- Design and develop 10+ Wordpress website use of custom post type, custom field, plugins, and jQuery to create interactive features.
- Efficiently resolving all cross-platform/browser issues, Optimize PageSpeed with an average 90% score of GTmetrix and 96% score on Google PageSpeed.

Key Achievements:

- Promoted to team lead on 15 design projects in 2018, 30% more projects led than any other team members.
- Created and Implemented SEO strategy that improved organic search traffic to corporate blog and website by 28% YoY.
- Created a 150 pages training manual from scratch and led bi-weekly training sessions for "digital marketing" course and received 4.9 scores out of 5 by student and management.
- Consistently achieve high-quality assurance ratings of more than 97% over a 24-month period on 18 design projects.
- Competently utilize Kanban process improvement techniques to ensure the most cost-effective production process.

GraphicPeople Web Developer April 2013 - October 2015 (2 years 7 months) Banani, Dhaka

Work with the team of NOKIA and MICROSOFT. Created 500+ static and animated HTML5 Banner ads for DoubleClick, Yahoo, Sizmek, Microsoft and others ad server. Managed code deployment, releases, bug fixes, and enhancements by the grunt, git, and webpack.

- Worked with a team of designers, product owners, and engineers to build new design and improve the current website UI/UX of the NOKIA and MICROSOFT.
- Developed 300+ graphic design projects (logos, websites, mobile apps UI, advertisements, infographics) that have increased client/company transactions by an average of 20%.
- Saved the time and budget over 16% by building an app in 14 weeks with HTML5, JavaScript that creates HTML5 banner ads BACKUP IMAGE automatically.
- Designed and coded bulletproof cross-platform responsive email templates, tested on 18 real devices and 37 email clients for several promotional programs sending out a weekly average of 2.5 million emails.
- Designed UI from inception to final product and successfully launched brand new GraphicPeople website which increased unique visitors by 30%.

• Increased productivity scores, created by 50+ reusable banner ads templates by Photoshop Scripts, Smart Objects & HTML5 that minimized each designer and developer an average of 8 hours per week.

BRAC

Flash Developer (Contract)
September 2012 - October 2015 (3 years 2 months)
BRAC Centre, Dhaka

Hired for developed custom interactive eLearning solutions used Flash with ActionScript 2.0 & 3.0 for NCTB primary education program. Organized, designed, customized, and generated 100+ storyboard with university professors. Created 20+ animated character, eLearning video, graphics, and animation.

- Prepared more than 800min humorous e-learning 2D animation and videos from start to finish for the kids education program.
- Converted total 17 primary curriculum books to flash interactive animated digital book.
- Designed and Developed 60+ interactive math games by used Flash with ActionScript 2.0 - 3.0 for kids education curriculum according to storyboard.
- Created backgrounds, special effects, characters and graphics for flash games and animation.
- Made and edited 2 episodes of Meena cartoon for BRAC and Unicef education program.
- Recorded dialogue from 10+ voice artist, made adjustments to compensate and integrated with flash animation.
- Coordinate with art directors, animator, designers, video editor and Bangladesh gov authority to Integrated NCTB curriculum in various flash games and animation.

Serverpipe

Senior Graphic and Web Designer (Remote) August 2012 - July 2013 (1 year)

Las Vegas, United States

Worked remotely with award-winning US design and development team to create and update the visual design, WordPress sites. Optimized sites for usability, search engine optimization and accessibility.

- Designed 50+ website stages from concept to final hand-off to engineering and ensuring website function and stability across devices i.e. desktop, mobile, tablet.
- Created cutting-edge flash animated greetings card and holiday banners for American Greetings and that listed in most creative 10 cards.
- Designed and Developed 20+ business application user interfaces that minimized load-time by 17% and accelerated user experience.
- Worked remotely with 2 development and QA teams to ensure a proper and hassle-free implementation.
- Led front-end development and assisted 8 freelance graphic designers to create large-scale projects for fortune 500 clients.
- Establish and documented design guidelines, best practices and standards they ensure brand consistency.

Databiz Software Limited 2 years

Sr. Graphic Designer July 2012 - December 2012 (6 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Lead Graphic Designer received 95% client satisfaction scores. Completed projects 10% before goals with 25% higher UX scores than average. Finished several projects in debugging and app creation, including an e-commerce app that got the mBillionth award.

- Completed a total of 12 projects for 4 clients, representing over 60 employees.
- Managed the design process and communication among internal development team, CTO, early target customers.
- Redesigned existing company website to improve user experience and incorporated SEO techniques thereby increasing daily traffic by 16%.
- Saved the time and budget over 25% by building the service website in 5 months with the proper function
- Developed a brand new admin panel for purchasing agent business application, which would improve the efficiency of operating by over 30%
- Design and coded 30+ landing pages and integrated into WordPress to support in-house and client marketing and promotional needs.
- Supervising all technical aspects of multiple digital projects to increase conversion rate

Graphic Designer

January 2011 - June 2012 (1 year 6 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Successfully developed the corporate brand identity and designed 120+ websites, received 95% positive feedback from clients.
- Developed 20+ Wordpress templates for advertising and design agencies.
- Created cutting edge 10+ animated flash intros, 100+ banners, and webbased advertising.
- Create static mockups as well as clickable prototypes/wireframes using Axure, HTML, CSS, Photoshop, and Illustrator.
- Worked side by side with development and QA teams to ensure design integrity which helped usher consistency in all the product deployments.
- Designed 26 mobile app UI for iPhone and Android that winning an award.

J. K. Group Of Industries

Graphic Designer

July 2009 - December 2010 (1 year 6 months)

Savar, Bangladesh

Promoted 3000+ employees textile industry. Developed new color separation technique with 10% higher performance than previous designer. Completed jobs 15% before targets with 95% client scores.

- Created an average 8+ t-shirt design a month for clients and merchandiser and prepared color separated file for printing house.
- Collaborated with 4-person creative team of designers to organize and develop large-scale projects for clients including H&M, CALVIN KLEIN, and TOMMY HILFIGER.
- Meeting and Communicated with clients to understand what they want out of a project and helping them get those ideas out in a workable way.
- Work between cross-functional teams such as buying house, merchandiser, printing house, marketing.
- Designed for the brand and internal needs such as business cards, stationery, posters, t-shirts, welcome kits, flyers, handbooks, signage, and other branding and communication materials.
- Managed the company's printing section with 80+ employees and 10 advanced printing machines.

A-one Computer Training Center
Graphic Design Instructor
March 2008 - January 2010 (1 year 11 months)
Mymensingh, Bangladesh

Researched, analyzed and created training curriculum and schedules for 2 courses and present training programs six to eight times a week. Received 100+ student thank-you letters and 98% positive comment scores.

- Achieved over 1000 hours of training on Graphics Design and Flash Animation.
- Planned organized and developed training materials that met specific needs for Graphic Design course, received 4.8 scores on a 5 point of scale by management.
- Delivered high-quality training presentations to student/audience of graphic design and they assessed me with 5.0 scores out of 5.0-point scale.
- Mentored new hires, resulting in 4 being promoted to new positions.
- Created weekly agendas, goal setting, shift, and training schedules for the team.
- Designs & illustrations promotional materials for events, such as t-shirt, mugs, pens, gift cards, packaging, company brochures, and business cards.
- Managed customers and clients on a daily basis, building rapport and retaining quality relationships.

Education

freeCodeCamp

Front End Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering · (2017 - 2018)

Polytechnic Institute Mymensingh

Diploma in Engineering, Electronic Engineering (2006 - 2011)

ACME IT (NIIT)

Diploma, Graphic Design